Prajjawal Agarwal

Stony Brook, NY, USA

+1 (631) 431-4882 | prajjawalagarwal@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/prajjawal05 | github.com/prajjawal05

ABOUT ME

Current Graduate Student pursuing Master of Science in Computer Science at Stony Brook University, NY. Have an industry experience of more than 3 years of working as a full-stack software developer. Loves solving challenging problems and mentoring junior developers, got promoted to SDE-2 within a year. Worked on several cross-team projects and even delivered several projects single-handedly.

EDUCATION

SUNY Stony Brook

New York, USA

 $Master\ of\ Science\ in\ Computer\ Science$

Aug 2022 - Dec 2023

Indian Institute of Information Technology Allahabad

Prayagraj, India

Bachelor of Technology in Information Technology - CGPA: 8.73/10

Jul 2015 - Jun 2019

EXPERIENCE

Software Development Engineer II

May 2020 - Aug 2022

MindTickle

Pune, India

- Took complete ownership over the Authentication and Rule Automation team for a while, leading them in each project and becoming a POC for all stakeholders.
- Implemented a file uploader system that processes the file with socket communication to the frontend. It was eventually used as a platform for other uploads on top of which other teams built domain services.
- Designed multi region routing stack for serving different customer traffic from different regions. This was essential to onboard companies wanting their data in only particular region.
- Introduced GraphQl and led frontend projects within the team while introducing latest upgrades for faster development cycles.

Software Development Engineer I

Jun 2019 – Apr 2020

MindTickle

Pune, India

- Built a query framework for frontend and backend that would maintain user selections across filters. This resulted in ease of bulk operations and increased usage.
- Architected a processor that would break any large task into chunks and decrease the time taken. This also improved the end user visibility through the states maintained.

Software Engineer Intern

Jan 2019 - Jun 2019

MindTickle

Pune, India

- Built a customer facing frontend application using React and Redux-Saga for serving automation rules. This was done as a part of UI overhaul.
- Did a comprehensive study comparing UI frameworks which was used when deciding a path for company stack.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages familiar: Java, Python, GoLang, Javascript, Typescript, SQL, N1QL

Databases used: Couchbase, Elasticsearch, PostgreSQL, DynamoDB

Libraries/Frameworks: React, Relay, Redux-Saga, Express

Miscellaneous: Git, Docker, Amazon Web Services (AWS), GraphQL, gRPC, Node.js

Research Based Projects

Learning Based CPU Frequency Governor | Data Mining, Linux Kernel, C++

 $Jan\ 2018 - Jun\ 2018$

- Study of frequency and temperature of CPU cores to create a governor that maintains frequency to save energy.
- Built a Linear regression model for frequency and temperature.

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Teaching Assistant (TA): Programming Abstractions at SBU.
- Volunteered at Prayaas, a student led organisation for teaching underprivileged students during undergrad.
- Working Committees Member, IIITA: Acoustics & Media Society (2016), Training and Placement Cell (2018).